Guide to the United States Steel Corporation National-Duquesne Works Records, 1890-1985 AIS.1991.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Employee Relations, 1930-1985; II.
  - Health, Hygiene, and Safety, 4.
    - Safety Microfilm
      This section includes microfilmed injury reports from 1969-1972, as well as safety statistics from the National Works. Monthly reports list the number of accidents by department and detail those that had occurred in the twenty-four hours prior to the report's release. From these, trends in accident frequency and severity can be studied.
      - U.S. Steel Corp. National Works Safety Activity Reports; Injury Reports, 1970-1974 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 6, Reel 64)
      - U.S. Steel Corp. National Works Injury Reports; Safety Statistics, 1968-1972 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 6, Reel 65)
      - U.S. Steel Corp. National Works Safety Statistics, August 1968- September 1970 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 6, Reel 66)
    - Medical Records
      These are the medical records of former employees of the National Works. The original documents were not salvageable, so the Archives Service Center created microfilm copies before they were destroyed. These records contain information about the typical plant worker's health while at the Works, including any injuries sustained while on the job, physical examination results, and details of any treatment administered at the plant hospital.
      - U.S. Steel Corp. National Works Medical Records; "Deceased and Pensioned", 1965-1975 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 6, Reel 67-78)
      - U.S. Steel Corp. National Works Medical Records, "Quits and Transfers", 1965-1973 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 6, Reel 79-93)
  - Employment, Placement, and Employee Activities, 5.
    The documents in this subseries detail the hiring and discharge of employees at the National-Duquesne Works. Termination files detail the grounds for dismissal and employment documents list the worker's nationality and military service, among other things. The activity and affirmative action reports outline the number of workers at the plant and divides them by race and gender. Broadcast sheets provide a list of all employments, terminations, and status changes, such as promotions, within the given year. Applications for the Work's 1960s Electric-Resistance Welding facilities are also included. Photographs of the annual apprentice dinner can be found in a separate box in media storage.
    - Termination, Employment, Lost Check, and Transfer Listings, 1956-1971 (Box 247)
    - Change in Employment Status, Foreman and Others, 1957-1968 (Box 248)
    - Employment and Transfer Notices, 1960-1965 (Box 249)
    - Employment Listings, 1963-1971 (Box 250)
    - Electric-Resistance Welding Applications, 1960s (Box 251)
    - Applications, 1969 (Box 252)
    - Broadcast Sheets, Activity Reports and Service Awards, 1975-1982 (Box 253)
    - Employment Records and Production and Maintenance Memos (Box 254)
    - Activity Reports (Box 255)
    - Foremen's Tests (Box 256)
    - Management Position Applications (Box 257)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (Box 258)
    - College Recruiting (Box 259)
  - Training, 6.
    These records contain information regarding the training of new or promoted employees. Documents include questionnaires and advice about how to become a better and more efficient leader.
    - Management Training, 1950s-1970s (Box 260)
    - Management Training and Training Subject Files, 1960s-1970s (Box 261)
    - Management Training and Development (Box 262-268)
    - Job Instruction Training, Leadership (Box 269)
    - Effective Speaking and Leadership Training (Box 270)
    - Safety Training Tests (Box 271)
    - Reports and Safety Training (Box 272)
    - Training Brochures (Box 273)
    - Training Documents (Box 274)
  - Rate Administration and William J. McShane Files, 7.
    William McShane began working for the National Tube Company in 1946. By 1953, he had become the supervisor of Organization Planning and Rate Administration. Some of his duties were to appraise the abilities of managers and initiate changes in the organization, as well as salaries or wages, of plant workers. After their merger he was responsible for these areas at both the National and Duquesne plants. McShane worked in Rate Administration and Organization Planning into the 1980s.
    Included in this subseries is a 1957 book with files on those working in the Duquesne Works' Central Operations. Information on their birthplace, nationality, education, salary, work history and military experience are available along with a photograph of each man. Personnel files regarding employees' removal from the payroll also include data on work history and salary. National Plant Rate Bureau subject files are alphabetized and include such information as management charts for every USX open hearth blast furnace.
    - Personnel Files, 1935-1950 (Box 275-277)
    - Wage and Salary Inequity Program, 1947 (Box 278)
    - Job Description, Wage Rate, and Inequity Program (Box 279)
    - National Plant Rate Bureau, D-1 to D-2 (Box 280-284)
    - Requests for Rate Change (Box 285)
    - McShane Correspondence and Business Papers (Box 286-288)
    - Duquesne, Exempt and Non-Exempt Salary, 1964-1969 (Box 289)
- Accounting, 1940-1971; III.
  The Accounting department at National-Duquesne Works worked with plant finances, including payroll and production costs. Cost sheet abstracts detail operations costs for various facilities at the plant. Information regarding salaries and incentive earnings are also present. The monthly progress reports outline the expenditures and profits of the Works. Files regarding exempt employees outline special situations in which those with administrative and executive positions are exempt from minimum wage and time and a half overtime.
  - Exempt Salary Sheets, 1952 (Box 290)
  - Labor Turnover and Accounting Department, 1945-1946 (Box 291)
  - Cost Sheet Abstracts, Monthly Progress Reports and Supervisor Incentive Earnings, 1940-1952 (Box 292)
  - Tax Liens and the Accounting Department, 1954-1971 (Box 293)
  - Non-Exempt Salaried Employees, 1950s-1960s (Box 294)
  - Accounting Bi-Weekly Salaried Employees, 1950s-1960s (Box 295)
  - Operating Department Rates, 1950s-1970s (Box 296)
  - Compensation, Exempt and Non-Covered Employees, 1960s (Box 297)
- Union Check-Offs, 1947-1976; IV.
  This series includes monthly updates regarding additions and deletions to the membership lists of Local Unions #1408, 2316, and 3074. Included are the names and jobs of the new members and the reason for a deleted member's removal.
  - Local Union Dues Check-Off List, 1947-1958 (Box 298)
  - Local Union Check-Off Runs, 1970-1976 (Box 299)
- Ledgers, 1941-1966; V.
  These ledgers were used at the National-Duquesne Works and contain employee names, citizenship/ethnicity, addresses, payroll and vacation information, and pension eligibility. Rosters contain an individual's clock number as well as notes on deceased, pensioned, terminated, transferred, and drafted employees.
  - Employee Roster, 1941 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 1)
  - Citizenship Verification, 1942 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 2)
  - Payroll, 1942 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 3)
  - Employee Roster, 1943 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 4)
  - Employee Roster, 1944 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 5)
  - Employee Roster, 1945-1946 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 6)
  - Employee Roster, 1947 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 7)
  - Employee Roster, 1948 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 8)
  - Payroll, 1949-1950 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 9)
  - Employee Roster, 1952 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 10)
  - Name and Address Listing, 1952 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 11)
  - Employee Roster, 1953 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 12)
  - Employee Roster, 1954 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 13)
  - Employee Roster, 1956 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 14)
  - Payroll, 1957 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 15-16)
  - Employee Roster, 1957 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 17)
  - Employee Roster, 1957-1958 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 18)
  - Employee Roster, 1959 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 19)
  - Payroll, 1962 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 20)
  - Employee Roster, 1966 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 21)
  - Employee Transfers, 1967 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 22)
  - Savings and Vacation Plans Roster, 1968 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 23)
  - Pension Eligible Employees (Box 299, Drawer 6, Volume 24)
  - Verification of Birth, Citizenship, and Pension Eligibility, 1942 (Box 299, Drawer 6, Reel 94)
- Presentations, VI.
  This series contains slide shows and their accompanying recordings, as well as training audio and video cassettes. Some slides and videos provide images of the National Works plant and its employees.
  - Slide Shows, 1.
    Within this subseries are slide shows that provide information on U.S. Steel and National-Duquesne Works' training for specific duties, compensation programs, and health and safety information.
    - Slide Binders (Box 300-301)
  - Recordings for Slide Shows, 2.
    The following audio tapes, labeled here as "Cassette," have corresponding slide shows and are arranged in order of how they appear in the binders.
    - "Camping at Camp Aliquippa" (Box 302, Cassette 1)
    - "Management Compensation Program" (Box 302, Cassette 2)
    - "Packing Clinic" (Box 302, Cassette 3)
    - "Oxy-Acetylene Handling and Application" (Box 302, Cassette 4)
    - "Oxy-Acetylene Cutting and Welding" (Box 302, Cassette 5)
    - "Introduction to Couplings" (Box 302, Cassette 6)
    - "CRT Operations" (Box 302, Cassette 7)
    - "Force" (Box 302, Cassette 8)
    - "Introduction to Fluid Power" (Box 302, Cassette 9)
    - "Intro. to Air Valves and Simple Circuits" (Box 302, Cassette 10)
    - "How to Tame a Machine" (Box 302, Cassette 11)
    - "Roll Pipe with Pipe Hook" (Box 302, Cassette 12)
    - "The Little Things That Count" (Box 302, Cassette 13)
    - "Intro. to Safety Belts and Lanyards" (Box 302, Cassette 14)
    - "Introduction to the Blooming Mill Indoctrination Program" (Box 302, Cassette 15)
    - "Rolling Mills Safety Hook up Program" (Box 302, Cassette 16)
    - "Andy Tells Steve about Rescue Breathing" (Box 302, Cassette 17)
    - "Caring for Bearings" (Box 302, Cassette 18)
    - "Roller Bearing Basics" (Box 302, Cassette 19)
    - "'It Could Happen Here' Fire Prevention" (Box 302, Cassette 20)
    - "Winter Driving and You" (Box 302, Cassette 21)
    - "Cylinders" (parts 1&2) (Box 302, Cassette 22)
    - "Fuses and Heat Pile Up" (Box 302, Cassette 23)
    - "Fuses and Overloads" (Box 302, Cassette 24)
    - "Commutators and Carbon Brushes Part One" (Box 302, Cassette 25)
    - "Commutators and Carbon Brushes Part Two" (Box 302, Cassette 26)
    - "Principles of Steam Tapping" (Box 302, Cassette 27)
    - "Human Relations Part I" (Box 302, Cassette 28)
    - "Human Relations Part II 'Practical Psy.' Action vs. Reaction" (Box 302, Cassette 29)
    - "Human Relations Part IV" (Box 302, Cassette 30)
    - "The Silent Killer" (Box 302, Cassette 31)
    - "'V' Belt Preventive Maintenance" (Box 302, Cassette 32)
    - "Gate Control" (Box 302, Cassette 33)
  - Recordings without Slide Shows, 3.
    The following audio tapes, labeled as "Cassette," and record do not correspond to any of the slide shows present in the binders.
    - "Compensation Program for Salaried Excluded, 1974" (Box 302, Cassette 34)
    - "Ken Boulden Material" (Box 302, Cassette 35)
    - "Bay 17 Threader Part II" (Box 302, Cassette 36)
    - "National Productivity" (Box 302, Cassette 37)
    - "Steel Com" (Box 302, Cassette 39)
    - "Duquesne Productivity" (Box 302, Cassette 40)
    - "Beating Today's Competition" (Box 302, Cassette 41)
    - "Principles and Interest" (Box 302, Record 1)
  - Video/Film, 4.
    This subseries contains video cassettes that were used at the National Works. Topics include U.S. Steel policies in the early 1980s and training to work on a variety of machines, among others.
    - "Nut & Bolt Fasteners" (Box 302, Cassette 1)
    - "Slab Identification" Texas Works, 1979 (Box 302, Cassette 2)
    - "Overcoming Objections" (Box 302, Cassette 3)
    - Coupling Seminar #3, April 25, 1979 (Box 302, Cassette 4)
    - "P.M.C. Boring Machine Operation" (Box 302, Cassette 5)
    - "P.M.C. Cut-Off Machine Operation" (Box 302, Cassette 6)
    - "P.M.C. Carbide Tapping Machine" (Box 302, Cassette 7)
    - "P.M.C. Tapping Machine Size Change" (Box 302, Cassette 8)
    - "United States Steel David M. Roderick" (Box 302, Cassette 9)
    - "Oilwell... Equipping Energy Industries Worldwide" (Box 302, Cassette 10)
    - "Identifying Job Related Behaviors" and "Effective Appraisal Sessions" (Box 302, Cassette 11)
    - "Strategies for the 80's... Employee Recognition", 1981 (Box 302, Cassette 12)
    - "U.S. Steel's Product Marketing", 1982 (Box 302, Cassette 13)
    - "U.S.S. Realty... USS Realty Development", 1981 (Box 302, Cassette 14)
    - "The Value of Video Training" (Box 302, Cassette 15)
    - "Accident Investigation Report", June 28, 1982 (Box 302, Cassette 16)
    - "Anti-Dumping" (Box 302, Cassette 17)
    - "Duquesne BOP Camera Shots" (Box 302, Cassette 18)
    - "The Environment... Energy and U.S. Steel", 1982 (Box 302, Cassette 19)
    - "Arbitration Case" (Box 302, Cassette 20)
    - "Financial Stability One of Our Strengths", 1981 (Box 302, Cassette 21)
    - "Marathon to U.S. Steel" (Box 302, Cassette 22)
- Photographs, 1943-1957; VII.
  This series contains photographs from apprentice dinners held by the National-Duquesne Works.
  - Apprentice Dinner Photos, 1943-1957 (Box 303)